[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Grosvenor Square, 1813.
Dearest reader,
the time has come to place our bets
for the upcoming social season.
Consider the household
of the Baron Featherington.
Three misses
foisted upon the marriage market
like sorrowful sows
by their tasteless<span style="style1">…
Tighter.
…tactless mama.
-Tighter!
-Is she to breathe, Mama?
I was able to squeeze my waist
into the size of an orange and a half
when I was Prudence's age.
Your sister shall do the same.
[gasps]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Far better odds might exist
in the household
of the widowed Viscountess Bridgerton.
A shockingly prolific family,
noted for its bounty
of perfectly handsome sons
and perfectly beautiful daughters.
[groans] I am already roasting.
Are you to complain
the entire day, Eloise?
Surely I cannot be expected
to bear these fashions the entire day.
I feel like a princess.
Do I look like one?
Do you truly wish to know
what I think you look like?
-On your left!
-Oh, Gregory!
Is our dear sister still not ready?
She's only been readying herself
the entire night.
You mean her entire life.
I shall run upstairs and hasten her along.
-Colin, wait. I'll do it.
-She likes me better than you, Benedict.
-Did she say that?
-Everyone says that.
[Eloise groans]
Daphne!
You must make haste!
Should you think she heard me?
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">How very perfect, indeed!
[Hyacinth] Stop it.
[sighs]
[Gregory] If you don't hurry up,
we're going to be late.
[indistinct chatter]
[indistinct chatter continues]
Any sign of him yet?
[sighs]
Should your brother wish
to be obeyed as Lord Bridgerton,
he must act as Lord Bridgerton.
Where is he, Benedict?
I do not know.
Hmm.
[both moaning, grunting]
[grunting, moaning continues]
-Anthony! You are here.
-Of course I am here, Sister.
I'd never miss such an important day
for you and our family.
No, you would just be late for it.
[exhales]
Shall we?
[indistinct murmuring, whispering]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Today is a most important day,
and for some a terrifying one,
for today is the day
London's marriage-minded misses
are presented
to Her Majesty the Queen.
May God have mercy on their souls.
Miss Prudence Featherington,
Miss Philipa Featherington,
and Miss Penelope Featherington…
all presented by their mother,
the Right Honorable Lady Featherington.
[attendees exclaiming, gasping]
[attendees chattering indistinctly]
[Lady Whistledown]<span style="style2"> It is only
<span style="style2">the queen's eye that matters today.
A glimmer of displeasure…
[attendees gasp]
…and a young lady's value plummets
to unthinkable depths.
[indistinct murmuring]
Miss Daphne Bridgerton,
presented by her mother,
the Right Honorable,
the Dowager Viscountess Bridgerton.
Flawless, my dear.
-[whispering] Did that truly just happen?
-[quietly] Keep smiling, dearest.
They are watching you…
now more than ever.
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">But as we know,
<span style="style2">the brighter a lady shines,
the faster she may burn.
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">It has been said that,
"Of all bitches dead or alive,
a scribbling woman is the most canine."
[women gasp]
If that should be true,
then this author would like
to show you her teeth.
[laughs]
My name is Lady Whistledown.
You do not know me,
and rest assured, you never shall.
But be forewarned, dear reader,
I certainly know you.
-You absolutely sparkled, Sister.
-[both giggle]
Come, now. I merely simpered and minced
in a pretty dress like everyone else.
Not exactly like everyone else.
Oh, I shall need to go
and visit with Penelope.
Her presentation was anything but…
What was it the queen called you again?
Flawless…
or some such thing.
Trust I was astonished
Her Majesty offered me,
out of 200 young ladies present,
a most gracious remark.
Yes, it was quite a distinction.
And now 200 young ladies
have a common adversary.
-I wish you luck, Sister.
-[Francesca] Eloise!
What? It is true.
My success on the marriage mart
influences all of your prospects.
We will all need to find love one day.
Indeed, a love as pure
as what Mama and Papa once shared,
if we are so fortunate.
I merely hope I am able
to continue such a grand tradition.
Your dresses have arrived.
[girls] Oh!
[girls giggling]
[Daphne] Oh!
This one is quite ravishing.
Mary Edgecombe wore
a similar shade last season.
And secured three offers
the very next day, one from an earl.
Mary Edgecombe,
now the Countess of Fulton,
apparently spent the last year
living in a cottage
hundreds of miles away from her earl.
She is miserable. It says it all here.
Do not tell me that is
yet another scandal sheet. Eloise--
No, no, this one is different.
This one lists subjects by name, in full.
-[gasps] Let me see!
-Wait. Wait!
-"Lady Whistledown."
-"Lady Whistledown"?
-[Eloise] The author.
-[Violet] Do we know a Lady Whistledown?
Surely Lady Whistledown
cannot be her true name.
What does it say, dearest?
She loathes the fact that we've been named
alphabetically, oldest to youngest.
-Your father and I found it orderly.
-Lady Whistledown finds "banality."
The papers were distributed
across town today without charge.
Without charge? What kind of author--
[both gasp]
[both chuckle]
Well, at least she has one thing right.
She has named Daphne
as the season's Incomparable.
She calls you
a "diamond of the first water."
Well, how lovely!
[chuckles]
[Lady Featherington]
I should not be surprised
if this Whistledown is revealed
to be Violet Bridgerton herself.
These pages certainly report
on the viscountess's family
with much indulgence, indeed.
The pages report nothing
but the truth, Lady Featherington.
Daphne has bloomed exquisitely,
and the sooner
she is taken from the market,
the better for the other young ladies…
even ones prone to hysterics
in front of the queen.
Ladies, hurry with your miniatures
before our guest arrives.
And, Penelope, put down that book at once.
You shall confuse your thoughts.
[Lady Cowper] So…
tell me about this cousin.
Joining you for the entire season?
She is a distant cousin of my husband,
and with no close female relative
to sponsor her debut,
Lord Featherington has directed me
to take her in for charity.
Hmm. You <span style="style2">are known to be quite charitable.
Precisely what this new rumormonger
should have published,
instead of erroneously specifying
that I shall only have three young ladies
under my care this year.
She knows nothing.
Unless you shall like to have
only three young ladies under your care.
I should gladly sit this season out.
Penelope is quite nervous.
This shall be her very first season.
I am not nervous, Mama.
What she is is two stone heavier
than she ought to be.
Mm, those blemishes on her face
are quite difficult to conceal.
Perhaps some arsenic and lead might help.
Should you allow me to delay only a year,
just as Lady Bridgerton
has done for Eloise,
I may remain dedicated
to my studies, perhaps.
The answer is no, Penelope.
You may wish to listen to her, my lady.
Shepherding four young ladies
through these endless rounds of affairs
at the same time…
[scoffs] Can you imagine the competition?
Well, how much competition
can this cousin provoke?
She came of age on a farm,
she has a mere four-figure dowry,
and as for her appearance…
Well, let us hope Miss Thompson
is more presentable
than the legions of unkempt animals
she has spent her entire life
-tending to back home. [laughs]
-Mm.
Lord Featherington's cousin
has arrived, madam.
[gasps] Now, remember to be kind, ladies…
and charitable.
The poor are our burden.
[clears throat]
Oh!
She's beautiful.
Good afternoon, Lady Featherington.
[exhales deeply]
Well, if this is not a sight
for my sore eyes!
My condolences,
Your Grace, for your father.
-Very kind of you.
-Kind of me?
You hated the man.
It is so wonderful
to see you, Lady Danbury.
Words I do not hear often enough.
Come.
You must excuse the, uh, disorderliness.
As you know,
I'm to host a ball this evening.
Yes.
I have managed to keep
the details of your return quiet.
But when those vulgar mamas discover
that there is an eligible duke
present at tonight's fete,
I shall be able to keep such a secret
no longer.
That is what I was hoping to discuss.
I have only returned to London
to deal with my late father's affairs.
I'm afraid
it leaves me no time to… socialize.
And so, whilst I appreciate
your most gracious invitation,
Lady Danbury,
I must ask you to accept my regrets.
Your regrets…
are denied.
-I suppose a brief appearance--
-Excellent.
You may leave
that flask you carry at home.
Most undignified.
[woman singing operatic scales]
[singing continues]
[both moaning, grunting]
Someone may hear us, my lord.
[Anthony] Mm.
[moaning, grunting continues]
One day, I shall seize that watch
and take it apart bit by bit.
That belonged to my father.
Should it disappear,
I would miss it sadly.
Then you shall know
precisely how I feel…
every time you disappear.
Stay with me today.
I'm afraid I cannot.
-[groans]
-Mm.
I must chaperone my sister
at the Danbury ball this evening.
-Daphne, yes?
-Mm.
What might they be like,
these grand affairs
your sister must attend?
You… would hate them.
-[chuckles]
-Every eligible lady of breeding
dressed in some lavishly trimmed frock,
bloodthirsty mamas at their sides…
[Siena chuckles]
…and wary fathers making arrangements
for only the most advantageous of matches.
And of course, without my father here,
that responsibility… falls upon me.
A significant duty, no doubt.
Someone must guard my poor sister
from the bucks and pinks,
ensure her virtue remains free
of any kind of defilement.
Daphne is fortunate.
Every woman is not afforded
such gallant protection.
Every woman is not a lady.
Of course not, my lord.
Siena.
Hey.
You have me…
protecting you too.
I will always protect you.
[Siena moans lightly]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">The season's opening ball at Danbury House
is a most highly
sought-after invitation, indeed,
for every darling debutante
from Park Lane to Regent Street
will be on display.
[rendition of "Thank U, Next"
by Vitamin String Quartet playing]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Titled, chaste, and innocent,
this is what they have been raised
and trained for since birth.
Tonight, we shall discover
which young ladies might succeed
at securing a match,
thereby avoiding the dreadful,
dismal condition known as "the spinster."
Oh, I do love to dance.
Do you like my flower?
We grow them in our very own garden.
I must show you my watercolors sometime,
if you desire to see them.
And she is quite proficient
on the pianoforte too.
[Lady Cowper]
Is that not the young lady
who was caught
with her gentleman last year
in Lady Mottram's conservatory,
unchaperoned?
She's lucky her gentleman agreed
to a hasty marriage
after she went and ruined herself.
Lightskirts.
[soft chuckle]
[indistinct conversation]
They're all staring, Mother.
Allow them to come to you, dearest.
Oh!
Look who's already setting his cap
at Miss Bridgerton.
Lady Bridgerton, Miss Bridgerton.
Lord Bridgerton.
I believe you have already been introduced
to my daughter Daphne, Lord Ambrose.
Uh, yes. We met at your brother's levee.
If I recall, my lord, you had just won
your first race at Newmarket.
His first and only, I believe.
Well, in that case,
let us hope his lordship
has found himself a new horse.
[chuckles]
I haven't had the pleasure of seeing you
at our club lately, Ambrose.
Should it have anything to do
with the unpaid balance
you left on our betting books winter last?
Ambrose is a cheat.
A man of any honor
ensures his debts are fully paid.
I did not realize…
Well, how could you have done?
It is the very reason I am here, Sister.
Let us take a turn about the room.
[chuckles softly]
He is rather pleasing.
He is rather here
to shuffle about hunting fortunes.
Trust Mr. Lewis knows
of your sizable dowry.
Leave him be.
-I presume you know of him too?
-Mr. Worthington. Second son.
We shall find better.
He is of dubious parentage.
I shall not have you making a life
with a poet, heaven forbid.
Nor an eccentric.
My word!
Anthony! Daph!
If the only gentlemen present this evening
are your brothers,
then we're in a great deal of trouble,
indeed.
You continue to say "we."
Did Mother tell you yet? About my tour?
I'm to begin in Greece.
-Greece? How adventurous, Colin!
-On guard!
[clears throat nervously]
Too late.
I already noted you.
-Lady Danbury.
-Good evening.
Miss Bridgerton,
you look rather lovely this evening.
Is there a reason
I've yet to see you on the dance floor?
All in good time, Lady Danbury.
You poor thing.
Who is that?
I'm sure I've never seen her.
Miss Marina Thompson,
a distant cousin of my husband's.
She's rather dowdy, is she not?
One of the Bridgerton boys
is joining the swarm.
Well!
[Lady Cowper] Most telling!
I imagine your household will be
a hive of callers in the morning…
Lady Featherington.
Where one suitor goes,
the rest will surely follow.
[Lady Cowper chuckles ironically]
Excuse me.
[indistinct conversation]
[quietly] There.
The duke. I would recognize him anywhere.
-Mama, where are you taking us?
-To meet the duke.
That man is not in our miniatures.
Make haste
before he should see Miss Thompson.
Your Grace.
[girls giggling, chattering]
Let me introduce my daughters,
Miss Prudence Featherington,
Miss Philipa Featherington.
[girls chattering excitedly]
I'm quite parched.
I shall fetch you
a glass of lemonade.
No. You have already done
so much for me tonight.
I shall return in a mere moment.
Good evening.
Small glasses.
-Lord Berbrooke.
-Tiny little things, are they not?
The glasses? I suppose.
Then the matter is settled.
I'm not entirely sure the matter
in which we discuss, my lord.
You've always amused me, Miss Bridgerton,
ever since I was a schoolboy,
and you were…
All but… five?
[chuckles]
[slurps loudly]
[exhales]
My brother, he summons me.
-Ah. [chuckles]
-Adieu.
Miss Bridgerton?
A moment, please! [chuckles]
[Daphne] Oh!
-[gasps] Pardon me.
-Forgive me.
Ah, yes. Wait just one second, thank you.
Tell me your name.
Your name, sir?
Am I honestly to believe
you do not already know my name?
[low] One moment. Yes, yes. Oh, hello.
[laughs boisterously]
If you desired an introduction, madam,
I do believe accosting me
to be the least civilized of ways.
Accosting you?
Truly, they will try anything.
Sir, that is not…
This is not…
-What is your name?
-[Anthony] Basset.
Basset!
-Bridgerton!
-Come here, old friend!
I heard news of your father.
-Deuce take it, you are no longer Basset.
-I shall--
Hastings! The Duke of Hastings,
now known for evermore.
The Duke of Hastings, is it?
-Right, Hastings, this is my sister.
-Your sister?
Daphne, Hastings and I know each other
from our days at Oxford,
days we shall not soon forget.
Yes. As I am well aware
of the company you keep, brother,
I am certain your days with His Grace
were most civilized, indeed.
Hastings, we shall need
to get together properly.
-I expect to see you at our club, then.
-Indeed.
Evening, Bridgerton.
Miss Bridgerton.
Daphne, I believe
Lord Wetherby is looking for you to dance.
-Is he?
-If only it weren't time for us to retire.
Daphne's anything but weary.
I shall stay with her.
-That would be lovely.
-Daphne…
there is nary a gentleman here
who would not take your hand.
You must think about this.
The most perfect thing to do now
is not to dance,
but to leave them all wanting more.
If anyone knows how this works,
it is your eldest brother.
Perhaps he is right.
Let us go.
[scoffs softly]
[door opens]
Miss! You've already awakened!
Have Cook prepare
as many biscuits as he can this morning.
Perhaps we might move a few extra chairs
into the drawing room too.
I do wonder which gentleman
will be the very first to call.
I have so much to ask of them all.
Well, let us get you dressed.
[Daphne sighs]
Anthony!
I did not expect
to see you here this morning.
It is terribly early for you, dearest.
I could not sleep for some reason.
All the excitement, I presume.
Am I the first gentleman to arrive?
How wonderful!
[rendition of "Girls Like You"
by Vitamin String Quartet playing]
[sighs]
Callers, ma'am. The Earl of Stafford
and the Marquess of Finley.
My word! Well, you should have
my colorful fashions to thank.
[clears throat]
For a Miss Marina Thompson.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Dearest reader, this author finds herself
compelled to share
the most curious of news.
And do you have
a large family, too, my lord?
It seems our diamond
requires a closer inspection.
Is there a problem, Lord Bridgerton?
I should think so. You are in my seat.
As such, an even rarer jewel
of only the most remarkable brilliance,
fire, and luster has been unearthed.
Her name, unknown to most,
yet soon known to all,
is Miss Marina Thompson.
Should you not be out
on your daily walk about the square, dear?
It appears as though it may rain.
[clears throat]
This author is left to wonder
whether Her Majesty might reconsider
the high praise
she once afforded Miss Bridgerton…
for we all must know what
the queen despises more than anything…
Being wrong.
And the drawing room at Bridgerton House
currently appears to be emptier
than the muddled head
of her dearest King George.
Well, I must be off to my club, then.
Sisters. Mother.
It follows that Lady Featherington
is to receive what she has always desired:
the season's true Incomparable
living under her own roof.
She must be overjoyed.
Is Miss Thompson so high in her instep
that she's unable to don her own slippers?
I should think not.
Has anyone else read
what Lady Whistledown has written of late?
Should anyone pay any heed
to what Lady Whistledown writes of late?
I certainly do not<span style="style2">.
Mama, perhaps we might attend
the upcoming Salisbury ball by ourselves
and the Merriweather tea too.
I believe that Anthony has already replied
on our behalf, dearest.
Apparently, he has managed
our social calendar through June.
He'll be there for the entire season?
Lady Whistledown has made her opinion
of our dear sister's fortunes quite clear.
Oh, enough about Lady Whistledown!
A caller for Miss Bridgerton.
Oh! [chuckles]
The Lord Berbrooke.
Lord Berbrooke.
Um… Uh… Come in!
May I help you
to some freshly prepared biscuits?
[chuckles nervously]
Eloise, allow some room
for his lordship, will you?
[Violet chuckles]
Eloise, are you not due
for a visit with Penelope this morning?
-I believe I should like to stay.
-I believe you should like to go.
[Eloise groans lightly]
[clears throat]
[Eloise chuckles]
Forgive me for not calling sooner.
I presumed
your affections were already engaged.
Now I know.
You and I were destined for each other.
[scoffing chuckle]
[Lord Berbrooke crunching loudly]
[inhales shakily]
And so, by Heaven, your love may burn
from the depths of my soul.
'Tis thee I shall earn.
Wonderful, wonderful.
Gentlemen, thank you for your calls.
Do not forget to bid Prudence, Philipa,
or even Penelope farewell as you go.
[suitors chatter indistinctly]
-A most wretched sonnet, indeed.
-Lord Byron he is not.
[chuckles]
I do not believe so. Good day, Pen.
Lord Berbrooke is harmless.
There will be others.
Lady Whistledown has all
but declared me ineligible…
worthy of the affection
of a detestable simpleton
and no one else.
Tell me, what others should ever want
such damaged goods now?
[Anthony]
You speak as if Lady Whistledown
were to be held in higher regard
than Her Majesty the Queen herself.
You give far too much credit
to some anonymous scribbler.
These musings, they're not true.
Only they are true, Brother,
and they are true because of you.
You have managed
to scare every worthy suitor away.
Whistledown has merely reported it.
I am looking out for you.
I am protecting you.
-It is my duty.
-And what of <span style="style2">my duty?
You have no idea what it is to be a woman…
what it might feel like
to have one's entire life
reduced to a single moment.
This is all I have been raised for.
This… is all I am.
I have no other value.
If I am unable to find a husband,
I shall be worthless.
Daphne, you're a Bridgerton.
[scoffs] It would be easier if I were not.
[clicks tongue]
Go on.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Ambitious mamas rejoice,
for the new Duke of Hastings continues
to grace our fair city with his presence.
And, oh,
what an impressive presence it is!
Lady Whistledown has written
about you again, Your Grace.
Would you like to read it?
It should be noted
that the duke has been overheard
announcing to mamas everywhere
that he has no plans of ever marrying.
This author wonders
which brazen matchmaker
shall rise to such a challenge,
for this competition is well underway.
You know, I do suppose if it were not
for an overzealous mother at every corner,
this time of year in the city
would not be so very dreadful.
Those mothers simply want
the same as you, I rather think.
For every last one of them
to choke on their daughters' hair ribbons?
For you to claim a wife, Hastings.
Are you not planning on taking your place
in society when you have a dukedom?
I have a title, which, as far
as I'm concerned, will end with me.
-But Hastings--
-Stop calling me that.
It was my father's name. Never mine.
And in any case, what of you?
What of me?
You are the firstborn Bridgerton
of a firstborn Bridgerton,
nine times over. Where is <span style="style2">your wife?
[waiter] Right away, sir.
Oh! Is your plan to fuck her forever,
your mistress?
You shall need to sire an heir.
I'm in possession
of something that you are not.
Brothers.
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">It has reached my ears
that Mr. Colin Bridgerton
shall be awarded the year's grand prize
when he sweeps Miss Thompson
off her pretty little slippered feet.
[Marina laughs]
You could always send the willow
back to that farm, madam.
As if Lord Featherington
would ever allow that.
[Marina laughs]
[both chuckling]
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">In other news,
a most peculiar suitor
for Miss Daphne Bridgerton has emerged.
Daphne…
[clears throat] Your caller.
Will it be just the two of us…
yet again?
[classical ensemble playing]
-Our box, Mama?
-Mm-hmm.
Lady Bridgerton!
Do join us.
Your Majesty, good evening.
You must remember my daughter, Daphne.
Yes.
She made quite an impression…
however fleeting it may have been.
[snorting chuckle]
I would like to welcome you both
to my box this evening.
I insist.
[overture playing]
They are saying her husband will not live
till the end of the month.
Surely another rumor provided
by that vicious, scandal-mongering writer.
Should her degradation know no bounds?
[operatic singing]
Lady Whistledown writes
about my family too.
Yet I suppose the duke
can withstand such scrutiny,
since he is, after all, a man.
His Grace was fortunate
to have you there with him as a child
after what happened to his mother. Awful!
-He is not what Whistledown writes.
-Nor is Daphne.
It would seem the two of them
have that much in common, then.
Matches have certainly been made
with far less.
What are you suggesting?
Lady Whistledown
merely writes what she sees.
Perhaps we need to help her
to see things a bit more clearly.
The duke is quite fond of gooseberry pie.
The very dish my cook is renowned for.
[both chuckling]
[yells]
[panting heavily]
[women giggling]
[Benedict] Haven't you heard
what we're talking about?
For all we know,
Whistledown may be some interloper
living in Bloomsbury, of all places.
What should be
so terrible about Bloomsbury?
That people there
actually work for a living?
She does seem to be someone with access.
-Who knows if Whistledown is even a she?
-[Anthony] Fair point.
Because she is simply too good
to be anyone but a man?
Well, I think it rather obvious
that the writer is Lady Danbury.
Lady Danbury enjoys
sharing her insults with society directly.
She would never bother herself
writing them all down.
Could it be Lady Featherington?
-No!
-[all laughing]
[Anthony] No.
You have yet to read
what Whistledown writes
of the Featheringtons, little sister.
You must forgive
this rather unruly debate, Your Grace.
-Nonsense. I find it entertaining.
-Oh! [chuckles]
All of you at one table,
even the children.
Well, I realize it may be unfashionable,
but we like each other. [chuckles]
Most of the time.
You should join us more often,
Your Grace.
Perhaps when we travel
to our country seat.
You would be most welcome.
[Hyacinth] Gregory!
Would you stop tossing peas at me?
Those peas were already there.
You cannot tell me what to do. I am older.
-And I'm taller.
-Children… [chuckles]
He does have a presence about him.
If rakish dukes were one's thing.
-I'm to spar with Jackson himself.
-You?
[Colin] Is that envy I detect
in your voice?
[Benedict] Judgment, brother.
I shall need to witness this.
You appear displeased.
Do I?
We find ourselves seated
beside each other, Miss Bridgerton.
I'd like to think
you're happy about that.
Perhaps, Your Grace, it would be better
if you refrained
from thinking about me at all.
It is simply surprising.
Yes! However is it possible for a lady
to offer anything other than a smile
whilst seated beside a duke?
…you regarding subjects much too…
-Even one of your reputation.
-You are aware of my reputation.
I am aware of your friendship
with my eldest brother.
If that were not enough, I am also aware
of the things a certain writer
has recently written of you.
Presumptuous? Clearly.
Arrogant? Most definitely.
You are a rake… through and through.
Tell me I'm wrong.
Who is to refrain
from thinking about whom again?
[chuckles] I assure you.
I am anything but interested in you.
-Good.
-Quite.
And I anything but interested in you,
the eldest sister of my oldest friend,
yet another recent subject
of a certain writer.
Chaste, neat, desperate.
-I shall have you know--
-To marry, that is.
Tell me I am wrong.
[laughs]
[Eloise clears throat]
Hastings, I'm so glad
you decided to join us this evening.
-It was most spontaneous of you.
-Not at all.
With Lady Danbury accepting
your dear mother's gracious invitation
on my behalf…
Well, however could I have declined?
[Violet] You must stay for dessert.
It's gooseberry pie, Your Grace.
Ah! Lovely!
[chuckles]
You were a reasonable mother
until your eldest daughter came of age.
-Anthony…
-This matchmaking scheme
you rather transparently concocted
with Lady Danbury, it will not work.
I can think of worse matches
for Daphne than a duke.
-I believe the two of you to be friends.
-We are good friends.
Which is why I know he has
absolutely no intention of marrying.
You must understand
all men make that assertion.
-Your… Your father--
-Do not bring Father into this.
Even if he were in want of a wife,
you would most certainly not have
the duke anywhere near Daphne.
I am fully subscribed to the belief
that reformed rakes make
the very best of husbands.
He will not make her happy!
Daphne deserves better.
And I know… I know you think
you are solving the problem,
but you are not.
And that is all I shall say
about the matter.
The duke will be joining us
as our guest at Vauxhall tomorrow evening.
I admit, it was not easy
to convince him to come.
-You overstep.
-She is my eldest daughter.
-Yet she is my responsibility, as are you.
-Responsibility?
Do not make this
any more difficult than it already is.
I wish to know something, Anthony.
Tonight, when you leave this study
that you continue to keep
at your family home,
are you to return
to bachelor lodgings across the square,
or will you pay a visit
to a certain soprano that you tend to
in an apartment that you pay for
on the other side of town?
Relying on your younger brothers
to one day do the job that you cannot.
You like to speak of responsibility.
My dear son!
Of duty?
Pray tell, what should you know of it?
I sit with her in that drawing room.
Do you know what I see?
A young woman who is terrified
because she knows what kind of life,
what kind of future, awaits her
should you continue to get in her way.
[Anthony scoffs]
If your father was still here,
Daphne would already have been matched.
The man would have made an arrangement
with an old friend.
The man would have done
what was now necessary.
So you must ask yourself
are you merely an older brother,
or are you the man of this house?
I cannot see you anymore.
I… I do not understand.
It is not for you to understand.
I must do what is necessary.
You said you would always protect me.
You promised to care for me, my lord.
And now…
What shall I do now?
You shall leave.
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">Be it shame or slander,
seduction or smear,
there is but one thing
that humbles even the most highly-regarded
members of our dear ton…
a scandal!
Well, dear reader, it should seem
that all of Grosvenor Square
has been left to ponder
a rather scandalous question, indeed.
Might one former diamond's
recent fall from grace
turn out to be
the most damning scandal of all?
[lively orchestra playing]
Pen.
Colin.
-I did not know you would be here.
-Sorry to disappoint.
-[chuckles]
-Have you seen Miss Thompson?
She is ill.
My mama had to stay home with her.
Papa had to chaperone.
I'm quite enjoying
the fact that he is here.
Mama would never allow me
to wear a dress like this.
Not, uh, yellow enough, I think.
[chuckles]
Mr. Bridgerton.
I believe you owe me a dance this evening.
And I have only one more space
remaining on my card at present.
How convenient. [gasps]
-Penelope, I did not see you there.
-[Penelope gasping]
I'm afraid I cannot offer you
that dance, Miss Cowper.
I am to escort Miss Featherington
to the floor.
[fiddle music playing]
[guests laughing, cheering]
[indistinct conversation]
The resemblance is remarkable.
You look just like him.
Your father.
[MC] Ladies and gentlemen,
a most extraordinary event
is about to take place.
Right this way!
Come! Come!
[humming softly]
[gasps nervously]
-Madam.
-Yes… Varley?
[clears throat]
[MC] It is with great privilege
I present Vauxhall's
newest spectacle of illumination.
Feast your eyes above
and allow all that is radiant
to overwhelm you!
[guests gasping]
[guests exclaiming loudly]
[MC] Wonderful light!
Thank you!
[guests chattering excitedly]
Is it not the most bizarre?
[gasps] Look, Brother.
What is it?
Lord Berbrooke's barony
is over 200 years old.
His lineage is legitimate.
He has had an excellent education,
possesses no debts,
never hurt an animal or a woman,
and is even a decent shot.
To speak strictly,
there is nothing wrong with him.
-What should any of this--
-You are to marry him.
-Nigel?
-I had to find you a husband, Sister.
Now, be grateful it is done.
It should be just as easy
to fall in love with Lord Berbrooke
as with anyone else.
I will not hear of this.
[sighs]
You haven't bled.
It's been over a month since your arrival,
and you haven't bled.
[sighs]
I suppose I should be happy.
Up until now,
I've had no legitimate excuse
to dispense with you.
But when Lord Featherington hears of this,
when your own papa hears of this…
-Please…
-I suppose I should be happy.
And if it were guaranteed
that my own ladies would not be affected
by your revolting recklessness,
I would be!
Do you even know who the father is?
What I know is
that you shall never understand.
-What was that?
-You shall never understand!
Someone like you,
living this ridiculously charmed…
Did you think I wanted to come here…
to be around people like you,
so out of touch, so superior?
Ah!
[breathing shakily]
Whatever are you doing?
Nigel, not now.
"Nigel?"
Are we to drop the honorific so soon?
I suppose as your husband--
You will never be my husband.
I will never marry you.
My brother, he…
He made a mistake.
Do you think yourself better than me?
[Daphne] It'd be best for you to leave.
You should be thanking me.
I'm your last hope.
No one wants you, Miss Bridgerton.
-[Daphne] What are you doing?
-You'll find out.
[Daphne] Stop it!
Let go of me!
[grunts]
[Berbrooke moans]
[Daphne gasping]
Your Grace… I had no intention--
Of knocking the climp flat out?
[gasps]
Well, I must say, I am impressed.
What are you doing out here?
Avoiding certain people.
-People?
-Mothers.
They are people, I suppose.
You are coming from the Dark Walk.
It is merely a few steps away.
-What would you know of the Dark--
-The Dark Walk is merely a few steps away,
and I am alone with two men.
You are only with one man. The other is--
I'll be compromised just the same.
Do you have any idea what would happen
if someone even suggested that I--
I must go.
Marry me, Miss Bridgerton.
Now, as far as proposals go,
that may be the least romantic of all.
I suppose if someone were to find me here,
it would be one way out of marrying him.
You cannot possibly be thinking
of marrying him.
If I am unable to secure another offer,
there may be no alternative.
Unlike you, I cannot simply declare
I do not wish to marry.
I do not have such a privilege.
Yes, I was surprised to learn
you no longer have a line of suitors
around every square in London.
I am in no need of your derision, sir.
I do not mock you. I am being sincere.
I know
of what this Lady Whistledown has written.
Trust I possess as much contempt
for the author as you do.
She's all but issued a challenge
to London's most ambitious mamas,
encouraging, provoking them to--
Claim you as their prize?
Do not worry, Your Grace.
I believe such a win
would be promptly forfeited, indeed.
I must go this way.
You, through those trees.
Perhaps there is an answer…
to our collective Lady Whistledown issue.
[fireworks popping loudly]
[dramatic music plays]
We could pretend to form an attachment.
[dramatic music intensifies]
[Simon] <span style="style2">With you on my arm,
the world will believe
I've finally found my duchess.
Every presumptuous mother
in town will leave me alone,
and every suitor will be looking at you.
You must know
men are always interested in a woman
when they believe another,
particularly a duke,
to be interested as well.
You presume Lady Whistledown--
I presume she'll deem us
to be what we are.
[Simon] <span style="style2">Me, unavailable.
You…
desirable.
Stare into my eyes.
Here.
Closer.
If this is to work,
we must appear madly in love.
-It is an absurd plan.
-I find it quite brilliant.
Provided you do not wish to marry me,
and I do not wish to marry you,
whatever should you have to lose?
[dramatic music escalates]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">For those not in attendance
at the Vauxhall celebration,
you missed
the most remarkable coup of the season.
It appears Miss Daphne Bridgerton
has captured the interest
of the newly returned Duke of Hastings.
How the young miss secured
her newfound suitor
is yet to be determined.
Yet, if anyone shall reveal
the circumstances of this match,
it is I.
Yours truly…
Lady Whistledown.
[dramatic music crescendos]